This is my entire wardrobe. I have one
shirt in a few colors,
one pair of jeans, some sweatshirts, and
a couple jackets. I also have a few
items for special occasions. 90% of the
time, I'm wearing the same exact thing.
I love the simplicity, but at some
point, simple became lazy. Now, I wear a
t-shirt and gym shorts pretty much every
day, [music] and my wife isn't
impressed.
>> You need to get it together. You're
pushing 40.
>> And neither [music] am I. So, I hired a
professional stylist to help makeover my
minimalist wardrobe.
>> Well, you can't even say it.
>> The real question, is it enough to win
over my wife? This video is sponsored by
Squarespace. More on them later.
>> Uh, what did I get myself into, Sally?
>> Are you nervous?
>> I'm a little nervous about this. This is
a lot. This is a lot. I flew to
Melbourne to be styled by the
incomparable Sally McKinnon.
As an author and educator, she's made a
name for herself as one of the most
sought-after stylists in Australia. And
for some reason, she replied to my DM
and agreed to give me a fashion
makeover. Sally isn't a minimalist, but
what I love about her approach [music]
is that she pushes back against some of
the worst trends in the fashion
industry. She encourages people to
restyle and repurpose what they already
have in their closets rather than
constantly rushing out to buy [music]
the latest trend. Whether she can fix my
style without compromising my minimalist
principles, that's another question.
>> That's it. That's That's the everyday.
>> That's the everyday. These are the
Lululemon infamous shorts, aren't they?
>> It looks so much worse when I'm looking
at it in a photo.
>> Having said that, that's what people are
seeing when they're looking at you.
Yeah, that is what clothing does. And I
think that's what most people
underestimate is what their clothing
says about them.
>> How fashion forward are we going? like
how how how much can I push out of my
comfort zone. I want to explore that
today, but I also don't want to go so
far that I don't recognize who I am. I'm
giving you the direction today. You
know, I'm kind, you know, you're
following me along. I'm going to make
suggestions. You're going to try things
on and I'll ask you how you feel and
what you think of things. And if you
don't like something, then off it goes.
It's back on the shelf. You know, it's
no use you going home with anything
today. uh that's that's that you don't
actually love and that you can't wait to
[music] get home and wear.
>> All right, here's shop number [music]
one.
>> Okay.
>> Okay, Matt, our first stop is Infamale,
a great Melbourne brand designed and
made right here in Melbourne. And the
first thing I thought I would like you
to try is this great cotton jacket. So,
over a knit, over a crew [music] neck
knit, over any of your t-shirts. So,
let's pretend we're not getting rid of
anything in [music] your wardrobe. We're
just adding a couple of really polished
pieces.
[music]
>> Can I ask you when when when I sent you
these photos and you had a look at my
wardrobe, what was your initial
impression?
>> Oh, well, clearly [music] minimalist,
simple, and bit boring.
>> Bit boring.
>> Yeah.
>> Check this out, Sally.
>> Yeah. What? Oh, you like the
>> Sally, look at that, Sally. That works.
You You know why you like it?
>> Cuz you look younger. Yeah. All of a
sudden, I have no idea how old you are.
You said 30 something. 30 something.
>> 38. 39. I forget. [laughter]
>> So, my brief to Sally was simple. First,
while I wanted to dress more mature, I
still wanted a minimalist wardrobe. And
second, I wanted to shop ethically and
sustainably. Today, we're starting out
with a few slow fashion retailers that
Sally picked out. Later on, I'm going to
be going even slower, looking for
secondhand items in thrift shops, as
well as digging through my own closet to
find things that I can reuse and
repurpose.
>> So, how do you feel about trying on
something like this?
>> I mean, actually, just looking at it,
like it it does it it feels a bit wider
than I would normally be used to. The
contrasting seam is like that's
different and bold cuz for me it's black
on black on black on black. So, yeah, I
think this is like quite a bit out of my
comfort zone, but uh I'm open to trying
it. Yeah.
>> Okay, cool.
>> Yeah.
Is he loving himself sick in there?
>> Yeah. Yeah, it's
>> I think I'm in shock. [laughter]
>> Oh my god. Who is this man?
>> Oh my god. What happened in there?
>> I think I need to start calling you
Matthew.
>> Wow. This is crazy. Check this out.
>> What? Oh, double zip. You got
>> Okay, can I just say without even
talking about the clothes first, your
face is alive. [music] Your eyes are
popping with that navy near your face.
>> Oh, really?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> The color is I really like the shirt.
The shirt is really nice. [music]
>> I cannot believe that neither of us knew
that your eyes were blue.
>> Sally never once measured me up. Didn't
so much as touch my waist and she's
pulling out outfits that are a perfect
fit for me. It's kind of crazy, but uh
she clearly knows what she's doing.
>> People aren't very good with change and
it's often a reflection of because it
challenges their perception. The only
one that really needs to be happy with
it and that you're doing it for is
yourself. So, welcome to Jay Dylan.
Now, we are in Swans.
[music]
So, this will be probably the most
tailored thing you'll have tried on
today.
>> I I see something here. [music]
>> I see what I see.
>> I got to actually try this on. But would
you call that minimalism?
[music]
>> Oh wow. Yo, I look cool. Look at that.
That's actually pretty crazy.
>> I think it's really nice on [music] you,
but I don't think maybe right now the
requirements of your life. What are
these going to replace in your wardrobe?
>> You my Lululemon shorts.
>> Your Lululemon shorts. Okay.
>> You ready, Matt?
>> I think so.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. I'm going to come out now.
>> Wa.
>> Look at this.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. What do you think?
>> I mean, actually, a clothes horse mash.
[laughter]
>> Look at this.
>> Like a model.
>> You You do look like a model.
>> Yeah. It's actually pretty good, isn't
it?
>> It's so good.
>> Quite surprised.
>> And I bet you could do a couple squats.
>> Oh, I could do some squats.
>> Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
>> I do feel I feel more like an adult. I
feel like an adult. Even though it is
like there it feels more
>> there's kind of like a weird blend where
it's like casual but a little bit
dressed up as well.
>> It's weird, isn't it?
>> Yeah. It's weird. [laughter] I like it.
>> Matt, I think we need to take him for a
spin.
>> Okay.
>> Because you've got a pretty big decision
to make now.
>> Yep.
>> Team black or team navy?
>> Okay. So, when I work with clients like
you who really want a very minimalist
kind of capsule wardrobe, they want
minimal pieces with maximum efficiency,
I often say you kind of got to pick one
base color to work from. And it's either
team navy or team black. See what what
you land on, what you feel more
comfortable with, what feels more you
after today.
>> At the end of the day, I walked away
with a couple pieces from local makers
in Melbourne. Now, I want to explore
some thrift shops and secondhand
options.
>> This is like my second time ever thrift
shopping.
>> Wow.
>> Or op shopping.
>> Op shopping in in a land of Oz. It's
called op shopping.
>> Okay. Yeah.
>> Since I have very little experience with
this, I asked Nina Gabbor to help. She's
a sustainable fashion advocate and a
lifelong thrifter herself.
>> Even though we're out shopping, I don't
want to feel pressured to buy something.
>> Exactly.
>> I feel like sometimes when I go out and
I'm like, I'm shopping, I need to buy
something. Like, I need to for it to be
successful, I need to go home with like
a bag with clothes in it. Yeah, that's
part of our conditioning, right? We're
conditioned to be consumers [music] from
birth.
>> We don't even It's not even a thought.
We just consume.
>> I don't like this. I feel a little bit
like I'm in the Backstreet Boys.
>> You look like [laughter]
>> a little bit, right? Like
>> you look like a Backstreet Boy. Can you
do a little Backstreet dance or
something?
>> Maybe that's insane. That's insane.
[music]
>> I keep asking myself why I'm doing this.
Like, yeah, it's a bit selfish. This
whole experience has been really fun and
has pushed me out of my comfort zone and
I've already started to feel more
confident in how I dress.
>> Working from home, hot chocolate, you
know, when you take a break. Yeah.
>> But I really think the biggest reason
I'm doing this is to impress Nat. We've
been together more than 12 years now and
we're a long way from those early days
when I would actually put effort into
what I wore. Raising two little boys has
been so much harder than either of us
could have imagined. It's just been so
physically and mentally draining and
it's taken almost every second of
connection time we've had together.
Those early years of courtship now feel
[music] like a distant memory.
>> Oh, it doesn't fit, boys. Does it fit?
>> Right. Like everybody's losing like you
don't see this off camera. Everybody's
losing their minds. Nina, look.
>> I love I love score.
>> Can you tell it's a woman's jacket?
>> No, you can't. You can't tell it's
[music] a woman's jacket. Definitely
something I'd pick out for you. $10.
$10.
What?
>> Underneath all of this, it's really just
me trying to court Nat again to light
the spark, to reintroduce a bit of
romance into our relationship again. And
as I get ready to reveal my new look to
Nat, I honestly feel like a kid in his
mid20s [music] again in New York City
trying to impress his new Australian
girlfriend. I'm just not sure if she's
ready for this kind [music] of change.
Guys, this jacket, it is so cool. Don't
look at what I'm wearing underneath.
This is still the same old Lululemon
shorts. Real quick, this video is
sponsored by my good friends over at
Squarespace. My sister Madison has her
very own slow fashion business where she
sells secondhand and pre-loved clothing,
trying to give them new life. She hasn't
gotten around to building a website yet,
so I offered to do it for her using
Squarespace.
>> Oh my god, I'm so excited. Yay.
>> Okay, let's start with the domain name.
Bingo. I like [music] this template.
She's already got brand colors, so I'm
going to plug those in. [music] No
website is complete without some really
strong copy. I asked her to send me
through some photos and videos, and so
I'm going to be adding those now to the
about page, the homepage, and the
contact page. Finally, and most
importantly, we need to set up her
online store through Squarespace. So,
we're going to do that now by importing
[music] her entire catalog. And here's
the final result. Let's see what Madison
thinks.
>> Oh my god.
>> Wow. Wait, you're so good at this.
[laughter]
I didn't even know that you were
supposed to have all this stuff. I'm
like, wait, this all makes so much
sense.
>> Oh my god, I love it.
>> So, if you want to see why I've trusted
Squarespace for the past decade with my
own website and why I trusted them with
Madison's website, go to squarespace.com
to start your free trial. And when
you're ready to launch, go to
squarespace.com/mattella
to get 10% off your first purchase of a
website or domain. When you're ready to
get started, just use that link or the
link in the description below this
video. And that goes a really long way
in supporting my channel and allowing me
to do really big dumb videos like this.
Thanks for your support.
>> Take a bit of a step. Perfect. One step.
>> Okay.
>> And then
>> Oh gosh.
>> I've got you. One more. And then you
feel that ledge. You're going to step
down.
>> Oh, okay. Gotcha.
>> And then we're going to move on through.
>> What have you guys done with my husband?
[laughter]
Like, is he also blindfolded?
>> Yep. Perfect. And now you're going to
sit down on the couch that is behind
you.
>> Okay. Wonderful.
I'm going to give you this.
Okay.
>> Three guesses what it is. Oh my gosh.
It's popcorn. I can smell it. [laughter]
>> Yes.
>> Oh yeah. I'm ready. Oh, sorry. Yeah.
>> What? [laughter]
Good evening, lady
[laughter]
and welcome.
[gasps] Let me please introduce to you
the star of our show this evening.
You've seen him in YouTube videos.
You've seen him having cold showers.
You've seen him having emotional
breakdowns publicly in front of millions
of people. Tonight, you get to see him
in a way you've never seen him before.
This is Matt Styled.
Oh my god.
[laughter]
[screaming]
Interesting. Wow. [laughter]
>> All right, Matt, talk us through your
wardrobe.
>> Yeah. Well, you know what? Uh, styled by
Sally.
>> Wow.
>> Um, so this is an informal
uh jacket.
>> Yeah.
>> Double zip.
>> And that's Latin for informal.
>> Oh,
>> is it?
>> I don't know. [laughter]
probably is.
>> Yeah, I'm guessing.
>> I think the big thing here is the pants.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I mean, yeah. I
haven't seen you in non-black denim in
what, seven, eight years.
>> There's nothing wrong with black denim.
>> Yeah. Sorry. [laughter]
>> Sorry.
>> Uh, this shirt, I don't know if it looks
familiar.
>> No, I didn't even know that you've had
this before.
>> This is our wedding shirt. This is the
shirt I wore at our wedding.
>> I didn't even know that you owned it.
>> Here you go, Jeeps. [laughter]
Um, so yeah, I uh I didn't know I owned
it either. And then uh I was just
looking through the closet and I found
it.
>> I Oh my gosh, you look you look like a
different person. Really?
>> It's hot.
>> I like it. You like it? Sally's genius
is that since I'm a a short guy,
>> a short king.
>> Short king. Thank you. Accentuate
[laughter]
the legs and Yeah.
>> I love the whole look. Like it's super
actually like it's giving a little bit
like femininity which I haven't normally
seen from you. Do you own the belt? Is
that a new belt?
>> This is from our wedding, too.
>> Are you just wearing your whole wedding
outfit?
>> Pretty much. [laughter] Yeah, pretty
much. All right, so that's fit number
one.
>> It's 50% your wedding outfit.
>> I know. Yeah. [laughter] Well, reduce,
reuse, recycle, you know.
>> Oh,
I love this.
>> You like it?
>> Yeah. This looks amazing.
>> Yeah. This is more of like a chill vibe.
$10.
>> Stop.
>> $10.
>> This is a $10 uh secondhand denim jacket
brought back to life.
>> I want to wear that. I'm I'm feeling
that. Yeah.
[singing]
>> I love it.
>> This is all I've ever wanted. [laughter]
I can't tell you how hard it's been to
get Matt into like a nice woolen jumper.
>> Here's the here's the trick that [music]
Sally taught me, right? It's like I
would normally put it on like this,
>> but she's like, "Shrug your shoulders
>> and then let it drop down." And then you
got the waist right there. Again,
accentuates the legs. Elongate the legs.
[music]
[singing]
can handle whatever was thrown at you.
This is weekend. This is weekend map.
>> So, this is secondhand.
>> Get out.
>> Yeah, I got it online. And actually,
finding secondhand white linen is quite
difficult.
>> Yeah, I think it's perfect.
>> I like how the stripes elongate your
legs.
>> Everything's about elongating my legs,
apparently. [laughter]
>> I really need some help with my legs.
>> May I please introduce to you someone
who'd like to ask you out [music] on a
date?
>> [music]
>> Oh wow. Oh my gosh.
Wow.
This is incredible.
You look amazing. This is not you. Like
this is someone else. Like what? Stop.
>> Yeah.
>> Can I touch it?
>> This is cashmere, my darling.
>> Really? Oh, this is so nice, too.
>> Facebook Marketplace, the only place
Divine Kashmir this
>> Yeah. Yeah. And the shirt. I love how
it's like speckled.
>> Yeah. Yeah. A little speckly.
>> Oh, that's so you. I really love it. Oh
my gosh.
>> Shout out to Casia
>> Facebook Marketplace. Well, specifically
Cassie's son.
>> Yeah.
>> Who grew out of it.
>> So, there's three different ways that I
could style this. When we go out,
obviously like this is when you're going
out and then we'll take it off.
This is style number two.
>> I really like that shirt.
>> Extra button on
>> with the white tea underneath. It looks
so cool. And that blue looks so good on
you.
>> Can you see my eyes?
>> My eyes blue.
>> Yeah, your eyes are blue.
>> Wow.
>> Thank you. Are you worried about me
doing daycare drop off wearing this?
[laughter]
>> I'm going to do all the drop offs and
pickups from now on. You just stay at
home. It's totally fine.
>> Yeah. So, this is uh this would be style
number three.
I love that shirt. I think that's my
favorite item that I've seen so far.
That and the um sweater, the knit.
>> Yeah.
>> And the shoes have a blue um [music]
lace or no blue lace. Yeah. Oh, yeah.
So, these the shoes these shoes are from
Jay Dylan.
>> They're a really good line.
>> Very very comfortable. I could wear I
could wear these every day.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, they're really cool. I like those a
lot.
>> You are so cool. What?
>> I love you.
>> A I love you, too. You look amazing.
>> Thanks for [music] doing this.
>> Of course. You look amazing.
>> Thanks. Let's go on a date.
>> Yeah. Plan it.
>> Do you want to?
>> Yeah,
>> I can plan it.
>> Yeah.
>> Little jab.
>> Well, I need to [laughter] Yeah,
exactly.
>> I feel like a third wheel.